Keyword match types determine how closely the keywords you bid on match the shopping queries customers
are using.
So let's see when you might want to use Phrase Match.
Take a set of blue cotton sheets that you're advertising and you've included blue cotton sheets
as a keyword.
If you're using the Phrase Match Type, your ad may display when customers are browsing for items
using all three of those terms – blue, cotton, and sheets.
In this order, plus close variations, like plurals.
If customers' shopping queries include other terms before or after, your ad may also be eligible
to appear.
But if they include these terms in a different order, or not as a complete phrase,
your ad wouldn't be shown.
Use Phrase Match after you've reviewed your search term reports
to see how shoppers are browsing for your items.
It's best for more specific keywords, also
called long-tail keywords, to help drive consideration and conversion.